xmatters.com 2018-05-10

# Privacy Policy | xMatters

Effective Date:  February 11, 2018

This Privacy Policy applies to the [xMatters website](https://www.xmatters.com/) and the xMatters customer portal, owned and operated by xMatters, inc. (collectively “xMatters,” “we,” “us,” or “our”). This Privacy Policy describes how xMatters collects, uses, shares and secures the personal information you provide, as well as the human resources data transferred to us for processing on behalf of our customers, as well as the human resources data of our employees. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. The use of information collected through our service shall be limited to the purpose of providing the xMatters service to our clients.

**EU-U.S. Privacy Shield  
**xMatters participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. xMatters is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles. To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the [U.S. Department of Commerce’s Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

xMatters is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under each Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. xMatters complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, xMatters is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, xMatters may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S. based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

xMatters has further committed to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) for EU employees, and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner for Swiss employees, with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning human resources data transferred from the EU or Switzerland, respectively, in the context of the employment relationship and employee data that it processes in its role as a service provider.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**Collection and Use of Information on the xMatters Website  
**We may collect the following personal information from users who visit our website:

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name and password
  * Information about your business such as company name and job title
  * Work and salary history

We use this information to:

  * Assess the needs of your business to determine suitable products
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Send you marketing communications
  * Respond to employment inquiries
  * Improve our website and marketing efforts
  * Conduct research and analysis

**User Data Supplementation –** We purchase marketing data about our customers from third parties and combine it with information we have already collected to help us ensure the data is accurate and complete. xMatters will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

When you download and use our Services, we automatically collect information on the type of device you use and the operating system version.

We send you push notifications from time-to-time in order to update you about any events or promotions that we may be running. If you no longer wish to receive these types of communications, you may turn them off at the device level. To ensure you receive proper notifications, we will need to collect certain information about your device such as operating system and user identification information.

We do not ask for, access or track any location based information from your mobile device at any time while downloading or using our Mobile Apps or Services.

We use mobile analytics software to allow us to better understand the functionality of our Mobile Software on your phone. This software may record information such as how often you use the application, the events that occur within the application, aggregated usage, performance data, and where the application was downloaded from. We do not link the information we store within the analytics software to any personally identifiable information you submit within the mobile application.

**Collection and Use of Information Through the xMatters Service  
**xMatters collects information under the direction of its Clients, and has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. xMatters works with its Clients to help them provide notice to their customers concerning the purpose for which personal information is collected. We collect the following kinds of personal information from our Clients:

  * Contact Information such as name, email address, mailing address, phone number
  * Unique Identifiers such as user name and password
  * Information about your business such as company name and business type

We use this information to:

  * Submit notifications, emergency warnings and updates to individuals on the behalf of our Clients
  * Assess system health and volume metrics and performance data
  * Send you requested product or service information
  * Respond to customer service requests
  * Administer your account
  * Send you marketing communications on an opt in basis

xMatters will retain personal data we process on behalf of our Clients for as long as needed to provide services to our Client. xMatters will retain and use this personal information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

**Disclosure of Information  
**We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.

**Service Providers and Sub-Processors  
**We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as submitting promotional email communications and emergency alerts to you on the behalf of xMatters. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. xMatters may transfer personal information to companies that help us provide our service to our Clients. Transfers to subsequent third parties are covered by the provisions in this Policy regarding notice and choice and the service agreements with our Clients.

**Legal Disclaimer**

We may also disclose your personal information:

  * As required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process
  * When we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request
  * If xMatters is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our website of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information
  * To any other third party with your prior consent to do so

### Access to Information and Choice

**Data Controlled by xMatters  
**Upon request xMatters will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. You may access, correct, or request deletion of your personal information by making the changes within your account settings or by contacting us via one of the methods listed below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe.

**Data Controlled by Our Clients  
**xMatters acknowledges that you have the right to access your personal information. xMatters has no direct relationship with the individuals whose personal data it processes. An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data should direct their query to the xMatters’ Client (the data controller). If requested to remove data we will respond within a reasonable timeframe.

**Opt-Out Preferences  
**Out of respect for your privacy, you may choose to stop receiving our marketing emails by following the unsubscribe instructions included in these emails, accessing the email preferences in your account settings page or by contacting us via one of the methods listed below.

**Security  
**The security of your personal information and our Clients’ information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as login credentials) we encrypt the transmission of that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security. If you have any questions about security on our website, you can contact us via one of the methods listed below.

**Tracking Technologies  
**Technologies such as cookies or similar technologies are used by xMatters and our marketing partners, affiliates, analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. We use cookies for to remember users’ settings such as language preference and authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

As is true of most websites, we also gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you. We may combine this automatically collected log information with other information we collect about you.

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/)  (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) ). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. xMatters also uses Google Analytics to monitor trends, performance, and the like. To learn more about Google Analytics, please see <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/partners/>.

**Changes to This Privacy Policy  
**We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you or our Client by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

### Additional Information

**Links to 3** rd **  Party Sites  
**Our Site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of xMatters. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.

**Blog / Forum  
**Our website offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us via one of the methods listed below. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Testimonials  
**With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us via one of the methods listed below.

**Referrals  
**If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend’s name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. xMatters does not store this information for additional purposes. If you believe that one of your contacts has provided us with your personal information and you would like to request that it be removed from our database, please contact us at [privacy@xmatters.com](mailto:privacy@xmatters.com).

**Social Media Features  
**Our website includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your internet protocol (IP) address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Contact Us

Your privacy is extremely important to us. Please send all privacy concerns to [privacy@xmatters.com](mailto:privacy@xmatters.com). Additional contact information can be found [here](https://www.xmatters.com/company/contact-us/). 12647 Alcosta Boulevard Suite 425, San Ramon, CA 94583, United States
